- 말해 줘
- 그래, 어서!
-Tell him.
-Shut up.
-Tell me what?
- 그만 해
- 무슨 일인데?
- 저거 봐, 쳐다보지도 못하잖아
- 뭔지 말해봐
You won't look at him.
I could use another
reason why women won't look at me.
여자가 날 쳐다보지도 못할
일이 뭔지 좀 알자
All right. All right.
Last night, I had a dream...
알았어, 할게
어젯밤에 꿈을 꿨는데
너하고 나하고...
...that you and I were
Doing it on this table.
둘이 여기서 했대!
아주 죽이는 꿈이구나
Excellent dream score.
그런... 꿈을 왜 꾼 건데?
Why would you dream that?
More importantly...
더 중요한 건, 나랑 좋았니?
...was I any good?
Well, you were pretty damn good.
아주 죽이더라!
Interesting. In my dreams,
I'm surprisingly inadequate.
이상하군, 내 꿈에서
나는 늘 고자거든
Last night, you seemed to know
your way around the table.
꿈속에 넌 탁자에서
꽤 능숙해 보였어
I love it when we share.
난 이런 얘기가 좋더라
You okay?
괜찮냐?
레이첼이 그런 꿈을 꾸다니
믿을 수가 없어!
I can't believe you two
had sex in her dream.
Sorry, it was a one-time thing.
미안해, 단 한번이잖아
I was very drunk, and it was
someone else's subconscious.
술에 취해서 무의식중에
한 짓과 같은 거야
The One With The lck Factor
Hello, Rachel.
안녕, 레이첼
Get off.
내려와
Ooh, give me. Can you see me
operating a drill press?
줘봐!
이거 다리미로 눌러야 하니?
I don't know.
What are you wearing?
글쎄, 속옷이니?
Why would you want to?
지금 그게 뭐야?
For short-term work. Till I get
back my massage clients.
잠깐 동안만 할거야
마사지 일을 얻을 때까지만
Pirates again?
또 불법으로 해?
No. Nothing like that.
아니, 그거와는 달라
나 진짜 멍청해
I'm just such a dummy.
I taught a "Massage Yourself at Home"
workshop. And they are.
'가정에서 할 수 있는
마사지법'을 가르쳤더니
이렇게 됐어
사무실에서 사람 구한다며?
Hey, Chan, she could work for you.
Thanks, Joey. That's a good idea.
고맙다, 기억력도 좋지!
나 할 수 있어
뭔데?
I could. I could do it. What is it?
내 비서가 2주간 휴가를 냈어
가슴 축소 수술을 받는대
My secretary's gonna be out.
She's having one of her boobs reduced.
It's a whole big boob story.
좀 크다는 뜻이겠지
-I could be a secretary.
-I don't know if it'd be your thing...
나 비서 할 수 있어
글쎄, 우리 일은
아주 정상적인 거라서...
... because it involves being
normal for a large portion of the day.
하루 종일 말이야
I could do that.
할 수 있어
-What's that?
-My new beeper.
그거 뭐야?
호출기 샀어
Why does a paleontologist
need a beeper?
고생물학자가 웬 호출기?
Is it for dinosaur emergencies?
Help. They're still extinct.
공룡의 비상사태를 위해서?
도와줘요
우리가 멸종 중이에요!
이건 캐롤이 분만할
때를 위해서야
It's for when Carol goes into labor.
내가 어디에 있든지 부를 수 있지
호출만 하면 돼, 55-짐보!
All she has to do is dial 55-JlMBO.
A cool number and
a possible name for the kid.
번호 좋다
그걸 애 이름으로 해
그럼 이따가 봐
-See you later.
-Off to see young Ethan?
- 꼬마 이던 만나니?
- 고마우셔라
Thank you.
How young is young Ethan?
Young?
얼마나 어리길래 꼬마야?
He's our age.
우리 또래야
When we were....
몇 년 전 우리?
-He's a senior in college.
-College?
대학 상급생이야
대학생?
Rob that cradle.
요람이나 흔들어줘라
He's smart and mature and grown-up.
똑똑하고 성숙한 어른이야
성숙한 어른?
걘 아직 애야
Mature and grown-up, he's a big boy.
This man-child has no problem
with how old you are?
그 꼬마는 네 나이가 상관없대?
No, of course not.
It's not even an issue...
물론, 없지!
문제가 안돼
내가 22살이라고 했거든
... because I said I was 22.
- 뭐?
-You what?
-What?
22살처럼 안 보여?
-Oh, I can't pass for 22?
-Well, maybe 25, 26.
25나 26은 돼 보여
-I am 26.
-There you go.
26살이잖아
맞췄다!
Can you hear that?
안 들리니?
들려
That'll stop
when you pick up the phone.
네가 받으면 소리가 안 나
-Oh, I'm on.
-Okay.
받아야지
Mr. Bing's office.
빙 사무실입니다
-Sorry, he's in a meeting.
-I'm not in a meeting.
죄송하지만, 회의중이신데요
뭔 회의, 나 여기...
Will he know what
this is in reference to?
빙 씨가 아시는 분이죠?
그쪽 번호도 아시죠?
And he has your number?
I'll see that he gets
the message. Bye-bye.
메시지를 전해드리죠
수고하세요
- 뭐야?
- 로스 안부전화야!
Ross says hi.
This is so fun.
What do we do now?
이거 재밌다
이제 뭘 하면 되니?
Well, now I actually
have to get to work.
난 이제 일해야 돼
"Most likely."
원래 그렇지
- 그럼 나가 있을게
- 그래
Okay, I'm gonna be out there.
All right. Bye-bye.
- 그럼, 바이 바이
- 바이 바이
Bye-bye.
-Yes?
-What you doing?
네?
뭐 하니?
Okay, windows are clean.
Candles are lit.
창문은 닦았고, 촛불도 켰고
벨트가 너무 조여, 바꿔야겠어
BeIt's too tight.
Gotta change.
Did I turn the fish?
Nope, because I made lasagna.
생선은 뒤집었나?
참, 이거 라자냐지
-Am I out of control?
-Just a touch.
- 나 너무 정신없지?
- 약간
I don't understand.
You've been dating this guy since...
난 이해가 안돼
이 친구 만난 게 언제...
... his midterms.
중간고사 때였나?
Why, all of a sudden,
are you so...?
그런데 왜 갑자기 그렇게...
-What?
-Could tonight be the night?
왜?
오늘이 바로 그날이니?
I don't know. He's a great guy...
몰라, 얘는 착한 애야
같이 있는 것만도 좋아
...and I love being with him.
But, you know...
일이야 생길 수 있지만
계획한다고 되는 게...
...things happen when they happen.
You don't plan these things.
-So, did you shave your legs?
-Yeah.
오늘 다리 밀었니?
응
Would you let it go?
It was just a dream.
그만 잊어버려, 그건 꿈이야...
그런다고 해서...
It doesn't mean
이런! 왔다!
애가 나온다, 나온다!
This is it. It's baby time!
All right, relax. Just relax.
Be cool.
진정해, 진정해
진정하라구!
Yeah, hi. I was just beeped.
안녕! 호출 받았어
No, Andre is not here.
Third time today.
아뇨, 안드레가 아니에요
오늘만 세 번째야
Yes, I am sure.
네, 그래요
I do not perform
those kind of services.
선생님, 저는 그런
서비스는 안 합니다
Services?
서비스?
서비스!
Oh, services.
Yeah, you want 55-JUMBO.
55-점보를 누르셨죠?
네, 그래요
맞아요, 저는 짐보예요
That's right.
JUMBO with a "U," sir.
You don't want me.
저는 절대 아니죠
Judging by his number,
I'd be a huge disappointment.
자꾸 잘못 걸리니
크게 실망되시겠어요
Alrighty, bye-bye.
괜찮아요, 바이 바이
괜찮아
어서들 와!
첫 출근 어땠어?
How was the first day?
Excellent.
Everyone was so, so nice.
아주 좋았어
사람들이 참 좋아
It pays to know the man
who wears my shoes.
당연하지
누가 소개한 건데
Me.
나야!
내가 챈들러 친구인줄 몰라
-I didn't tell anyone I knew you.
-Why?
- 왜 몰라?
- 왜냐면...
Well, because, you know.
They don't like you.
나한테 네 욕을 하니까
-What?
-I thought you knew.
뭐?
- 넌 몰랐니?
- 아니
-Who doesn't like me?
-Everyone.
누가 날 싫어해?
전부 다!
Except for....
누군 아니었는데...
No. Everyone.
아니, 전부 다
-What are you talking about?
-Don't feel bad.
그게 무슨 소리야?
기분 상할 거 없어
전에는 인기 최고였대
They used to like you a lot.
그런데 네가 승진하고 나서
너무 보스 티를 낸다는 거야
But you got promoted, and now you're
Mr. Boss Man. Mr. Big.
보스! 웃 상사 노릇!
Mr. Bing. Boss Man Bing.
-I can't believe it.
-Yeah. They even do you.
그럴 리 없어!
맞아, 직원들이 흉내도 내
They "do" me?
내 흉내를?
You know, like, okay:
응, 이렇게 해
"Could that report be any later?"
그 보고서는 나중에 봅시다
-I don't sound like that.
-Yeah, you do.
난 그렇게 안 해
- 챈들러!
- 바로 너야
"The hills are alive
with the sound...
이 산은 살아 움직이네
...of music."
음악으로!
"My scone. My scone."
- 내 케익!
I don't sound like that.
That is so not true.
난 안 그래
절대 안 그래!
That is so not
절대 아냐... 아냐...
That
Oh, shut up.
그래, 맘대로 해라!
-Did not.
-Up until I was 9...
정말?
난 9살 때까지 총구가
범죄자 이름인 줄 알았어
... I thought "gunpoint" was
a place where crimes happened.
왜 그런 생각을 했는데?
-How's that possible?
-It's always on the news.
생각해봐, 뉴스에서 그러잖아
"A man is being held up at Gunpoint."
한 남자가 총구에 강도 당하다
관광객이 총구에 질려버리다
"Tourists are terrorized
at Gunpoint."
And I kept thinking,
"Why do people continue to go there?"
그래서 생각했지, 왜 사람들이
그 놈을 못 잡을까?
I should go.
이제 가야겠다
그래
그럼...
-Unless
-What?
- 혹시...
- 왜?
여기서 자고 가도 돼
Unless you wanna stay over.
I mean, I'm going to. So....
나도 잘 거거든
Yeah, I'd really like that.
나도 그러고 싶어
여기 함께 있기 전에
미리 할 말이 있어
Before we get into any
staying-over stuff...
...there's something you should know.
설마 "내일 오전 강의가 있어"
Is this, like,
"I have an early class tomorrow"...
"고향에 벌써 마누라가 있어"
같은 건 아니지?
...or "I'm secretly married
to a goat"?
그 중간쯤이야
Well, it's somewhere in between.
You see, in a strictly technical
sense, of course, I'm not....
엄격하게 말해서 기술적으로
따지자면 그렇다는 건데...
Well, I mean, I haven't ever....
그러니까 내 말은...
Ethan?
- 이던?
- 응?
Are you a virgin?
너 동정이니?
If that's what you kids are
calling it these days, then...
네 또래들이 그런 단어를
쓴다면... 그래 맞아
...yes, I am.
I mean, you're just such a good kisser
I would never have known.
그렇게 키스는 잘하면서?
일단 해본 건 뭐든 잘해
Well, I've excelled at every level
I've been to, I just....
아직 그것만 못해봤어
I just haven't been to
that particular one yet.
I've kind of been waiting
for the right person.
그래, 정말 좋아하는
사람과 하고 싶었어
-Really?
-Yeah.
- 그래?
- 응
You do know I was talking
about you, right?
- 그게 바로 너인 건 알지?
- 알아
Wow.
You keep saying that.
왜 자꾸 그러니?
You know, you read about it.
You see it in the movies.
난 책도 보고, 영화도 봤어
Even when you practice it at home,
man, oh, man...
집에서 연습도 해봤는데
세상에...
...it is nothing like that.
이건 전혀 달라!
Listen, listen.
잠깐, 내 말 들어
You told me something
that was really difficult for you.
넌 참으로 힘든 말을
나한테 다 해줬어
And I figure if you can
be honest, then I can too.
그래서 말인데
나도 솔직하고 싶어
Don't tell me I did it wrong.
제발!
내가 잘못한 건 아니지?
아냐, 그건 아냐
넌 잘못이 없어
Nothing wrong about that.
좋아, 한다!
Here goes.
I'm not 22.
난 22살이 아냐
I'm 25...
난 25하고도...
...and 1 3 months.
13개월이야
But I figure that shouldn't
change anything.
그런다고 달라질 건 없어
우리가 몇 살이든 무슨 문제겠어?
What does it matter how old we are?
Basically, I'm nuts about you.
사실, 난 네가 좋았어
첫 키스 때부터 느꼈다구
I knew after the first time we kissed.
You didn't mention the Tic Tac.
네가 표현하지 않아도
혀끝에서 느낌이 왔어
I just thought
you were naturally minty.
나도 네 향기가
처음부터 좋았어
그러면 내 말도 들어봐
서로 솔직하기로 하면...
Listen...
...as long as we're
telling stuff...
나도 할말이 있어요
제 나이는 더 어려요
... I have another one for you.
I'm a little younger than I said.
-You're not a senior?
-Oh, I'm a senior...
상급생 아냐?
상급생은 맞아요
고등학교에서
...in high school.
그러니?
What we did was wrong.
우리가 일을 저질렀어
세상에!
I just had sex with someone who
wasn't alive during the bicentennial.
내가 10살 때 태어나지도
않은 남자랑 섹스를 했어
I just had sex.
난 드디어 했어요
Ethan, focus.
How could you not tell me?
이던, 정신 차려!
왜 말을 하지 않았니?
-You never said your age.
-It's different.
누나도 나이를 속였잖아요
그건 달라!
My lie didn't make one of us
a felon in 48 states.
너 때문에 나는
미성년자 성폭행범이 됐어
-What were you thinking?
-I was too busy falling
대체 생각이 있니?
난 몰랐어요
누나한테 홀딱 빠져서...
-Don't say it.
-ln love with you.
말하지마!
누나 사랑해요
-Really?
-Sorry.
그래?
죄송해요
Well, fall out of it.
제발 사랑하지 마라
You shouldn't be here.
It's a school night.
넌 여기 있으면 안돼
이건 보충학습이 아냐!
Oh, God.
맙소사!
I'm like those women
that you see...
이제 난 그 이름도 찬란한
여자들 중에 하나가 됐어
...with shiny guys named Chad.
I'm Joan Collins.
난 조안 콜린즈야!
Who?
누구죠?
Andre should be there
in about 45 minutes.
안드레가 45분 뒤에
거기로 갑니다
Yes, sir, the kimonos are extra.
기모노는 비용이
별도구요
Alrighty. Bye-bye.
네, 바이 바이
차라리 이게 쉽군
It's just easier that way.
-You told me about the last dream.
-No. Forget it.
전에 네 꿈을 얘기했잖아
아냐! 제발 좀 잊어!
Why not? Was I doing
something particularly saucy?
왜 그래? 내가 부분적으로
너무 외설스러웠니?
좋아
All right. Fine.
사실...
꿈에 너만 있던 거 아냐
You were not the only one there.
Joey was there too.
조이도 나왔어
All right.
좋다
Was there...
거기...
...anybody else there?
또 다른 놈 없었니?
아니
You sure? Nobody...
정말이야?
누가 사탕 같은 거 안 줬니?
... handing out mints or anything?
No, it was just the three of us.
아니, 우리 셋 뿐이었어
그럼, 설명 해봐
So was it you and Chandler...
너와 챈들러니, 너와 나니
아니면 너, 나, 챈들러니?
...then you and me,
or you, me and Chandler?
-You know what?
-What?
- 알고 싶어?
- 뭔데?
사실 그때...
나는 없었어
There were times...
...when it wasn't even me.
너희들 참 좋겠다
That is so sweet, you guys.
- 안녕, 모니카
- 어서 와
Mon, Ethan called again.
이던이 또 전화했어
모니카?
모니카!
-What?
-Ethan called again.
뭐?
이던이 전화했다구
-You're not seeing him anymore?
-No.
- 걔랑 이제 안 만나?
- 안 만나
Sometimes, things don't work out.
가끔 틀어질 때도 있지
This has nothing to do with him
needing a note to get out of gym?
그 꼬마가 체육시간에
허리라도 틀어졌대?
I did not say anything. I swear.
나는 말 안 했어
절대로 안 했어
-He stopped by.
-Next time you talk to him...
걔가 왔었어
다음에 걔를 만나면
...could you ask him which one
the strongest Power Ranger is?
파워 레인저 중에
누가 제일 센지 물어볼래?
Oh, my life is just so amusing.
Can we drop it now?
내 인생은 너무나 즐거워
이제 그만 좀 할래?
Sorry.
- 미안해
- 그래
"It's morphin'time."
변신 시간이다!
-Stegosaurus.
-Tyrannosaurus.
- 검룡이다!
- 티라노사우루스!
가봐야겠어
I gotta go.
머리가 아파
Head rush.
One more, and then I have to go.
한번 더, 이제 갈게
Cool.
됐다
Where you going?
어디 가니?
직장 동료들하고
생일 파티 가야돼
A birthday party
with some work people.
Work people? Nobody told me.
직장 동료?
나도 모르는데!
I know.
That's part of the whole...
널 좋아하지 않는 사람들끼리
모여서 노는 거니까
...them-not-liking-you
extravaganza.
A month ago,
these people were my friends.
이해가 안돼
한 달 전엔 모두 내 친구였어
I'm in charge,
but I'm not a different person.
내가 윗자리로 갔다고
딴 사람이 된 건 아니잖아
Then come, hang out. Let them see
what a great guy you still are.
그럼 오늘 같이 가서
함께 즐겨봐
네가 아직도 괜찮은
사람이라는 걸 보여줘
-You think I should?
-I really do.
- 꼭 그래야 할까?
- 그게 좋아, 그래
- 좋아
- 그래
- 우리 따로 가는 게 어떨까?
But could we not go together?
I don't wanna be the geek
who invited the boss.
상사를 초대한
사람이 되기 싫거든
-Hey, you okay?
-Yeah.
- 너 괜찮니?
- 응
그 녀석도 힘들 거야
-This can't be easy for him either.
-I know.
알아
걔는 이번 일을 잊으려면
시간이 좀 걸릴 거야
This may take some time
for him to get over it...
그래도 새벽 4시면
네 생각만 할거다
... but, then at four,
Muppet Babies is on.
월트, 받아
뒤로, 뒤로!
Go deep. Deep. Deep.
Sorry, Shelly.
미안해, 쉘리
See, with the fun?
거봐, 재밌어하지?
Last night was great.
어제 정말 즐거웠어
가라오케 기억나지?
The karaoke thing?
Tracy and I doing "Ebony and lvory."
트레이시와 내가 함께
노래를 불렀잖아
You were great.
But they still made fun of you.
잘했어! 그런데 아직도
네 얘기를 해
-What?
-Now you're Mr. Caring Boss.
뭐?
이젠 사람들이
네가 부담스런 상사래
Mr. I'm-one-of-you Boss.
난 보통사람, 보스다
여러분의 친구, 보스 빙
Mr. I-wanna-be-your-buddy
Boss Man Bing.
Then I don't get it.
어느 장단에 춤을 추냐
You know what?
I think you just gotta face it.
내 말 들어, 챈들러
그냥 현실을 인정해
넌 큰 사무실에서 일해
You're the guy in the big office.
You're the one that hires
and fires them.
사람들을 고용하고 해고해도
여전히 좋은 상사로 생각해
-They say you're a great boss.
-They do?
그래?
But they're not
your friends anymore.
직원들은 더 이상
네 친구가 아냐
-I just want
-But you can't.
- 그래도 나는...
- 그럴 수 없어!
But I just want
- 그래도 나는...
- 안돼
Are you gonna?
안 받아...?
캐롤과 암호를 바꿨어
Carol and I have a new system.
If she punches in 9-1 -1...
911이 찍히면 아기가
나온다는 뜻이야
...she's having a baby.
Otherwise, I just ignore it.
그게 아니면
다 무시할 거야
What about Andre?
안드레는?
오늘 아침에 사촌 네이선이
거기로 전화를 했는데
He got a call
from our cousin, Nathan.
Frankly, it was a little more
than I needed to know.
솔직히, 별로 알고 싶지
않은 내용이었어
안녕!
That was gonna be my opener.
항상 내 첫 대사였는데
Have you guys seen those
new hand dryers in the bathroom?
얘들아!
여기 화장실에 있는
손 건조기 써본 사람?
-I thought that was just a rumor.
-True story.
- 소문 아니었어?
- 진짜 있어
Look, I gotta tell you something.
봐요! 내 말 좀 들어봐요
난 17살이 아니에요
I'm not 1 7. I said that so you'd
think I was vulnerable.
그냥 모성본능을
일으키려고 그런 거죠
I'm actually 30. I have a wife
and a job. I'm your congressman.
난 사실 서른이에요
아내도, 직업도 있어요
누나보다 훨씬 위라구요
This is ridiculous.
We're great together.
모니카, 이건 바보짓이에요
우리 좋았잖아요
We can talk, make each other
laugh, and the sex....
함께 얘기도 하고 웃었죠
섹스도... 세상에!
I have no frame of reference,
but I thought that was great.
저는 사회에 기반은 없지만
그것도 괜찮잖아요
-lt was.
-Then what's the problem?
- 그랬지
- 뭐가 문제죠?
Ethan, it's....
이던, 우린...
It's icky.
세대가 틀려
"lcky"?
세대요? 고작 세대 때문에
끝낸다는 거예요?
You're actually gonna throw this away
because it's "icky"?
This isn't easy for me either.
I wish things were different.
나도 쉽지 않아
시대가 달랐으면 좋겠어
네가 나이가 좀 더 많거나
내가 좀 더 어리거나
If you were older
or I was younger...
...or we lived in biblical times...
아님 우리가
2백년 전에 살았으면...
-... I could really
-No, don't say it.
그런 말 말아요
사랑해
Love you.
-Are your hands still wet?
-Moist.
- 손에 땀났지?
- 응, 젖었어
건조기로 말리자
Let's dry them again.
이 마르가리타가 더 센가?
Or, like, "Could these margaritas
be any stronger?"
안녕, 챈들러
Hey, Chandler.
안녕하세요, 빙 씨
Hello, Mr. Bing.
어제 스티비 원더 노래
좋았어요
Loved your Stevie Wonder last night.
고마워요, 주 단위 보고서는
9시까지 내 방으로 가져와요
Thanks. About the weekly numbers, I'm
gonna need them on my desk by 9:00.
-Sure.
-No problem.
- 그러죠
- 가능합니다
You have to give them something.
네가 잘 좀 맞춰 줘
거스턴, 산토스 그리고
콧수염 난 친구는?
That was Gerston, Santos, and
who's the other guy?
- 페트리
- 페트리, 그래
-Petrie.
-Petrie. Right, okay.
Well, some people
are gonna be working...
저들 중에
일꾼을 뽑아야지
...this weekend.
주말 특근에!
너무 좋아
Oh, that's nice.
로스!
Ross.
- 로스?
- 여기 있어
I'm here.
You are?
그래?
우리 그럼... 와우!
We were just....
What?
뭐?
-Great. Now I'm having a baby.
-What?
나, 애 아빠 된다!
뭐?
I'm having a baby. I'm having a
드디어 애 아빠 된다구!
- 세상에!
- 나 이제...
-The phone, the phone.
-I don't have the phone.
- 전화 어딨어, 전화?
- 바로 저기, 전화!
로스?
I'm hurt.
나 아파
모니카, 가자!
얘들아, 애가 나와
Let's go.
Come on, people. Woman in labor.
나 아주 잘 뛰겠지?
-Look what I got going.
-Save it for the cab.
택시를 위해 아껴라
지금 뭐해? 뭐야?
우리 병원 가!
We're going to a hospital.
I can't look nice?
There are doctors there.
그런다고 화장도 못해?
남자 의사가 많잖아
- 조이, 냉장고 좀 포기해
- 알았어
-Joey, get out of the fridge.
-All right.
- 그게 뭐야?
- 배고플까봐
-What is that?
-For the ride.
- 그래, 택시 안에서...
- 있다 말해!
-Like in a cab
-Save it.
-Hating this.
-Monica, come on. Let's go.
그래, 나도 싫어
모니카, 어서 가자!
아기가 나온다구!
Baby coming.
I can't believe I'm gonna be
an aunt.
너무 좋아 죽겠어!
내가 고모가 되다니!
조카가 생긴다구!
-I'll have a nephew.
-That's nice. Get out.
넌 좋겠다!
가!
- 가자!
- 알았어
All right, I'm going.
I'm going.
그래, 간다, 가
자, 가자! 가자!
Here we go. Come on.
로스, 괜찮아, 가자
우리랑 가야지